Lesson 6  Grandmother's Birthday
祖母の誕生日
祖母の家に着くと、今日が誕生日だと分かりました。
When we arrived at grandmother's house,
we learned that today was her birthday.
みんな祖母に特別な贈り物をしたいと思いました。
All of us wanted to give her a special gift.
母は庭のきれいな花を贈りました。
My mother gave her a pretty flower from the garden.
父が古い家族写真を見せると、祖母はほほえみました。
My father showed her an old family picture,
and grandmother smiled.
妹は学校での長くておもしろい話をしました。
My sister told her a long, funny story from school,
そして、みんなで笑いました。
and we all laughed together.
わたしは祖母に新しい本を買いました。
I bought her a new book.
祖母は一人ずつにほほえみ、「みんな、ありがとう」と言いました。
Grandmother smiled at each of us and said,
"Thank you, everyone."
とても温かな一日でした。
It was a very warm day.